Welcome brothers and sisters to another
Wednesday question and answer where we
open up with the 10 Commandments that
God had written for the whole world to
keep. Brother Tenzel.
And God spake all these words saying,
I am the Lord thy God, which have
brought thee out of the land of Egypt,
out of the house of bondage.
Thou shalt have no other gods before me.
Thou shalt not make unto thee any graven
image,
or any likeness of anything
that is in heaven above, or that is in
the earth beneath, or that is in the
water under the earth.
Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. For the Lord thy God am
a jealous God,
visiting the iniquity of the fathers
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me,
and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain.
For the Lord will not hold him guiltless
that taketh his name in vain.
Remember the sabbath day, to keep it
holy.
Six days shalt thou labor, and do all
thy work. But the seventh day
is the sabbath of the Lord thy God.
In it thou shalt not do any work,
thou, nor thy son, nor thy daughter, nor
thy manservant, nor thy maidservant, nor
thy cattle, nor thy stranger that is
within thy gates. For in six days the
Lord made heaven and earth, the sea, and
all that in them is, and rested the
seventh day. Wherefore the Lord blessed
the sabbath day, and hallowed it.
Honor thy father and thy mother, that
thy days may be long upon the land which
the Lord thy God giveth thee.
Thou shalt not kill. Thou shalt not
commit adultery. Thou shalt not steal.
Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbor.
Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's
house.
wife, nor his manservant, nor his
maidservant, nor his ox, nor his ass,
nor anything that is thy neighbor's.
We read Exodus 21 through 17, and may
the Lord have a blessing to the reading
of his words. In Jesus' name we pray.
Amen.
From here on question and answer, you
can ask us a question and we'll answer
it according to the King James Bible.
And if we cannot find the answer, we
will seek further counsel to bring you
an answer at a later time. The questions
we will not answer are the vague
questions as well as the long scripture
questions and questions of debate. We're
not here to debate, we're here to spread
the true gospel of Jesus. So please, be
as direct as possible with your
questions so we can be as direct as
possible with our answers out of the
King James Bible. No other Bibles or
books will be acknowledged on this
program. Also, keep in mind this is a
live stream, so feel free to send in
your questions that pertain to
everlasting life. We just asking that
you keep them to a two scripture
maximum. Let me introduce you the family
that's on the panel this evening. We got
brother Dre.
Good evening. Brother Julius. Good
evening, everybody.
Brother Jerome.
Grace and peace.
Brother Tanzel.
Good evening.
Sister Deborah.
Good evening. Brother Sean.
Good evening.
And we have the guest caller with us and
I'm brother Cornell. Sister, what is our
first question of the evening?
Yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A.
Zion says, "Over the past 6 months, I
have lost my car, job, and apartment. I
don't understand.
Everyone says it's because I don't go to
Sunday church. They do and things are
going right with them. What am I doing
wrong?
Well, just based on information you gave
us,
um doesn't say whether or not you
go to the Israel of God or not, but
I would say that would be a great start.
But versus this Sunday church, uh that
has nothing to do with what has befallen
you.
And it doesn't state that anything will
get better by going there because
we keep the seventh day. The seventh
day, which is Saturday, and church is
the first day of the week, which is
Sunday.
But let us go into Exodus the 31st
chapter first. Exodus 31.
And let's see where the Sabbath, which
is Saturday, comes from and why we keep
it.
Exodus 31. Tenzel, read that verse 12
and 13 for me.
And the Lord spake unto Moses, saying,
Speak thou also unto the children of
Israel, saying,
Verily my sabbaths ye shall keep: for it
is a sign between me and you throughout
your generations; that ye may know that
I am the Lord that do sanctify you.
So, this is the Lord giving Moses
instructions and saying, "Hey, that he
want us to keep the Sabbath day, which
we know is the seventh day." Skip down
and read verse 16.
Go ahead.
Wherefore the children of Israel shall
keep the sabbath to observe the sabbath
throughout their generations for a
perpetual covenant. Uh-huh. It is a sign
between me and the children of Israel
forever.
For in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, and on the seventh day he rested
and was refreshed. So, we are following
the God that created everything, even
heaven and earth, and the seventh day is
the day that he rests. Go ahead.
And he gave unto Moses when he had made
an end of communing with him upon mount
Sinai, two tables of testimony, tables
of stone written with the finger of God.
So these commandments, keeping the
Sabbath day, was written with the finger
of God, and therefore it is a sign
between him and his people, which are us
who keep it. So we would recommend that
you continue to keep the Sabbath day,
which is Saturday, and if not,
you should begin to keep that. But let's
go into you ask why all these things are
befalling you. Well, let's go into um
that Hebrews, the 12th chapter.
Let's go into Hebrews 12, because
sometimes things
just happen.
Hebrews 12.
Let's pick it up at that verse five.
Hebrews 12
and five.
Because the Lord lets us know that
sometimes he's chastening us, and
sometimes things happen to us that
are not good, but we have to hold on to
God. Go ahead.
And ye have forgotten the exhortation
which speaketh unto you as unto
children.
My son, despise not thou the chastening
of the Lord, nor faint when thou art
rebuked of him.
For whom the Lord loveth he chasteneth,
and scourgeth every son whom he
receiveth.
Yep, so people can have their trials and
tribulations, and sounds like you're
going through some of your own, for
sure. Go ahead.
If ye endure chastening, God dealeth
with you as with sons.
For what son is
he whom the father chasteneth not?
Uh-huh. But if ye be without
chastisement, whereof all are partakers,
then are ye bastards, and not sons.
Right, so the Lord is always saying that
we have to endure what it is that we're
going through, because hey, if you stick
with him, you're going to win in the
end, no matter what you might be going
through right now. Hebrews 11.
Now, no chastening for the present seem
to be joyous,
but grievous.
Nevertheless, afterward it yielded the
peaceable fruit of righteousness unto
them which are exercised thereby.
So, we definitely know firm what you're
going through based on everything you
said, but I think you have to continue
to stay strong, serve the Lord, and hey,
and pray for sure.
But, uh anybody else got something
they'd like to add?
Well, I would
>> Ecclesiastes uh 9:11 says, "Solomon said
time and chance happens to everybody.
Sometimes it's just a test of your
faith."
That's it.
Guess caller. And I would
And I would suggest that he read the
book of Job.
Yeah.
>> That'll tell it all.
Yeah, and
yeah, you're right, because also I had
on there Job uh the first chapter.
And that verse I I had 21 and 22 on
there also. Let him read the Read the
whole the first chapter.
Yeah, read the whole the whole book of
Job, cuz
even though Job was going through it, he
stayed strong with God,
and he didn't sin with his lips, and God
blessed him twice as more on the other
end.
And God
called him a righteous and upright man.
Yeah. So, God called you righteous and
upright, that's what you got to be. And
the question is, why is it that all of
this happened to a God-declared
righteous and upright man?
That's why you read the book and find
out.
Yeah. Book of Job.
>> Yes, sir. All of it.
Yeah, and we uh
wish you the best in some of the
recovery of the some of those things
that you have lost.
All right. We hope that answers your
question as we move on to our next.
Next one. Miss Wade asks in Ecclesiastes
3:21,
"What does this mean the animal spirit
go downward?"
All right, let's go to that
Ecclesiastes.
3 and verse 21.
And when you get there, Tenzel, go right
ahead and the guest caller take it from
there.
Who knoweth the spirit of man that goeth
upward?
And the spirit of the beast that goeth
downward to the earth?
But the first thing is
he wasn't making a statement, he was
asking a question.
And that And that he is uh
uh let's let's back up a little bit and
show you where
the God that men and beasts also.
Let's
back up to Ecclesiastes.
18.
Yeah.
Okay, start reading there and read down
into it.
I said in my heart concerning this state
of the sons of men
that God might manifest them that are
that in that may
that they might see that they themselves
are beasts.
For that which befalleth the fall of the
sons of men befalleth beasts.
Even one thing befalleth them. As the
one dieth, so dieth the other.
Yea, they have all one breath.
So that a man have no preeminence above
a beast.
For all is vanity.
All go unto one place.
All are of the dust
and all turn to dust again.
But who knoweth the spirit
That's letting you know that man and
beast come from the same world, they're
doing the same thing
and they have the same properties. Go
ahead.
Who knoweth the spirit of man that goeth
upward, and the spirit of the beast that
goeth downward to the earth?
Now, that's the question. Who know
whether the spirit of of the man to go
up or not or spirit of a beast that go
downward? Who knows? Being that can't
nobody see the spirit that we're talking
to we talking about. So, let's find out
what spirit this is that the
Solomon is talking about in
Ecclesiastes.
Let's go first to Job 27th chapter and
read 1 through 3.
Moreover, Job continued his parable and
said,
As God liveth,
who hath taken away my judgment, and the
Almighty, who hath vexed my soul.
But all the while my breath is in me,
and the spirit of God is in my nostrils.
Now, look what it said. All of the while
my breath is in me, and the spirit of
God is in my nostrils. Now, let's go and
find out what God put in man's nostrils
when he created him.
Go into Genesis the second the second
chapter and read verse 7.
And the Lord God formed man of the dust
of the ground, and breathed into his
nostrils the breath of life.
And man became a living soul.
And man became a living soul. So, what
is that spirit that goes in the your
nostrils? That is the breath of life.
And when a man die,
or when a beast die, the breath leave
both of them. You don't know whether the
breath went up or down because you ain't
ever been able to see breath in your
life. Mhm. Who you ask the question, to
put it plainly.
When a man down a beast there, who knows
whether the breath of man goes upward or
whether the breath of man goes downward?
Nobody know. Being that you can't see
breath and you can't see air.
So, it's still a question. Who knows?
But, the spirit is the breath that we
breathe.
Right.
>> That's all I have to say.
All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next.
Next one. Brother Love says, "Help me
understand what time period second
resurrection happens. It seems like
right after Jesus 1,000 year rule, Jesus
turns over the kingdom to the Father.
When will the judgment line happen?"
All right. Brother Jerome, speaking on
behalf of the judgment, go right ahead.
Yeah, the uh second resurrection
actually happens
uh within the 1,000 year reign
uh of Christ.
Okay.
Uh but, let's go take a look at uh
Revelations 20
because
there's a verse that talks about uh
Satan being in the pit for 1,000 years.
Let's Let's go take a look at that.
Revelations 20, we're going to read
verse 2 through 3.
You get it, go ahead and read.
And he laid hold on the dragon, that old
serpent, which is the devil and Satan,
and bound him 1,000 years.
And cast him into the bottomless pit,
and shut him up.
And set a seal upon him, that he should
deceive the nations no more, till the
thousand years should be fulfilled.
And after that he must be loosed a
little season.
Okay, so he said after this thousand
years that he's in the pit
is fulfilled,
he said he going to be loosed a little
season. Okay? Now, he got to be loosed
before the eighth day
start, okay?
So, this little season is going to
happen within the thousand-year reign of
Christ when Satan is loosed out of his
um pit.
All right? Skip down to verse five.
But the rest of the dead lived not again
until the thousand years were finished.
This is the first resurrection. Okay, so
this thousand years right here, okay?
That ain't the thousand years where you
go right into the eighth day.
Cuz Satan ain't going to be loosed in
the eighth day.
No way.
Okay? So, uh
let's go to
um
let's go let's go to 2 Corinthians
because see the Lord's thousand years
is things that he got to deal with when
they come out of that great while when
they come out of their graves after that
thousand years expired within the
thousand-year reign of Christ, then
at some point you going to have a
judgment day,
okay? And you got some people that's
going to be coming up in that second
resurrection that's enemies of the Lord
that's got to be judged before that
white throne judgment, and that takes
place during the thousand-year reign of
Christ, okay? So, let's go to
uh
1 Corinthians the 15th chapter.
And we going to read verse 24
through 26.
>> Let me get it go ahead and read.
Then he come up with the end.
Add something to that when you get
through.
Okay. All right. We got you.
urgently
Go ahead.
Then come up with the end when he shall
have delivered up the kingdom of the
God, even the Father.
When he shall have put down all rule and
all authority and power.
For he must reign till he have put all
enemies under his feet. But the last
enemy the last enemy that shall be
destroyed is death.
Mhm.
But that's the last enemy that he got to
destroy within his reign within his
thousand year reign. So can you go back
to that um
Revelations
20?
Mhm?
You go back to 20?
Yeah, Revelations yeah, 20.
And pick it up at the 11 read 11 and
and 12
because
these people got to be judged.
And if they ain't in the lake of fire
I'm if they ain't
they ain't in the book of life
they going to get cast in the lake of
fire, okay? But pick it up at that 11
and 12.
And I saw a great white throne and him
that sat on it.
From whose face the earth and the
heavens fled away. And there was found
no place for them.
And I saw the dead small and great stand
before God. And the books were opened.
And another book was opened. Which is
the book of life.
And the dead were judged out of those
things which were written in the books
according to their works. Yeah.
And so if they not found in the book of
life
during that judgement okay? Then they
going to get cast in fire. But then as
you continue to read he said death and
hell was cast in a lake of fire. Right.
>> And that was the last enemy that he was
going
to put under his feet before his reign
was over with. Okay.
But guest caller you you want to ask
something.
Uh-huh.
You know
one of the things you have to look at
is that
I want you to read this verse five,
Revelation 20 and five.
But the rest of the dead lived not again
until the thousand years were finished.
This is the
>> Yeah.
And this is the first resurrection.
Right.
>> Reason I want to interject is because
the thousand years then
Jesus reign and Satan being put in
in the lake put in the bottomless pit
started on the sixth day, not on the
seventh day.
Because the Lord said the Lord is going
to come in the seventh month.
On the tenth day of the month. That's
the day of atonement. That's when the
Lord is going to come. So they can't
come on the seventh day. It's come on
the sixth day. And when Jesus feet touch
that ground
that's when his thousand year reign
start. So he ruled for a thousand years.
And when the thousand years are over
with the dead are raised, not within the
thousand years.
After
thousand years. But you still have time
left in the seventh day.
So in the seventh day
people going to be Satan going to be
loose.
He is going to go all over the world and
get rebellious people. These living
people. And they're going to try.
They're going to go up to Jerusalem and
and surround the camp of the saints.
Then fire going to down from the Father
and kill them. Then Satan is going to be
thrown
in the lake of fire. Once that's done,
then you going to have the white throne
judgment.
And that all happens on the seventh day.
But it all starts when the dead is
raised at the end of the thousand years
of peace, not within it.
So when the thousand years is over,
which you still have uh uh
let me see how many months left?
Cuz it it's it's translated into years.
You have years left.
So Satan should be loose.
You see the people that's living at the
end of the thousand years.
God going to rain down fire and kill
them. He going to throw the Satan in the
lake of fire, and they going to have the
white throne judgment.
All that will happen at the end of the
thousand years, but not the end of the
seventh day.
Throughout the whole white throne
judgment and everything is taken care
of. Then once Jesus is put out on death
and everything, and everything's in the
lake of fire, and everybody's going to
be God is God,
then that's going to end on the seventh
day.
And on the eighth day is when the
Father's kingdom going to come down.
Who do you rose? Let me think something.
But you what uh uh
kind of like
uh uh throws people off is that they
don't understand that Jesus
thousand years starts
in the seventh month.
And the tenth day uh
the sixth day.
And in the end,
when the thousand years is over with, on
the seventh month, and the tenth day of
the seventh.
So all the rest of that time you have
to raise the dead,
Satan deceive the people,
people killed from with fire, Satan
thrown in the lake of fire, white throne
judgment, and then Jesus Jesus going to
turn it over to the Father. All that
happened
just before the seventh day, but at the
end of the thousand years rule.
That's all I have to say.
All right.
Thank you for that.
As we move on to our next question.
Next question, Skywriter asks, "How do
you know
that the bottomless pit in Revelation 9
is actually talking about somebody being
there and nobody know knowing about it?"
All right, Brother Julius, how do you
know?
The Bible said that we have a more sure
word of prophecy.
Let's go to Revelation the 9th chapter,
and let's deal with this bottomless pit.
First thing you have to understand is
God works by time.
And when you look at John
when you read Revelations, which was
written by John
John is writing about future events.
He's writing about end-time prophecies.
He's writing about the East
Eastern European Union versus Russia and
her allies, the kings of the East. So,
he
didn't have helicopters and and
rocket launchers in his day.
But, he's describing the thing that he
see in the future
based upon the thing that he had in his
time. Let's look at it. Revelation 9 and
1. And the bottomless pit is is merely
uh a time where because God works by
time where the prophecy is going to be
revealed. Go ahead and verse 1.
And the fifth angel sounded, and I saw a
star fall from heaven onto the earth.
And to him was given the key of the
bottomless pit.
That is metaphorically speaking of the
time at the at the fifth angel sound,
now
it's time for the east and the west to
get ready and go
to war. Go ahead.
And he opened the bottom of this pit.
And there arose a smoke out of the pit
as the smoke of a great furnace.
And the sun and the air were darkened by
reason of the smoke of the pit.
>> So now, when you see weapons of warfare,
bombs, this stuff going on, and and and
the smoke of those uh bombs and and uh
high-tech uh military hardware,
it's so much smoke that it it blocks the
sun. So, it becomes dark and real black.
You're like a house that's on fire. The
smoke is black. Blocks out everything.
Go ahead.
And there came out of the smoke locusts
upon the earth. And upon them was given
power as the scorpion of the earth have
power. Now, John didn't have Blackhawk
and Tomahawk helicopters in his day, but
a helicopter looks like a uh uh
uh when it's flying, it looks like a
locust. And it's got guns in the front
and and tail gun that you could fire
from the back. So, this is what John is
looking at it. He's looking at these
Blackhawk helicopters flying and
shooting and firing missiles and
bullets. And he's doing his best to
describe in our day and time according
to the thing that he had in his day and
time. Go ahead, brother, verse four.
And it was commanded them that they
should not hurt the grass of the earth,
neither any green thing, neither any
tree,
but only those men which have not the
seal of God in their foreheads. Because
anybody that's not under the protection
of the Lord God of Israel, you are
susceptible in these areas of what is
war is going to be going on, you could
be killed. But if you're under God's
protection in a place of safety, you
going to see it but it ain't going to
come near you. Verse 5.
And to them it was given that they
should not kill them,
but that they should be tormented 5
months.
And their torment was as the torment of
a scorpion when he striking for man.
So now he is describing chemical or germ
warfare. Something that can disable you,
but you won't die.
But you want to die but you can't die.
But it's this is chemical and germ
warfare. One more version and that'll be
it.
And in those And in those days shall men
seek death and shall not find it. And
shall desire to die, and death shall
flee from them.
Give me one more version let's describe
this last one. Go ahead.
And the shapes of the locusts were like
unto horses prepared unto battle.
And on their heads were as it were
crowns like gold. And their faces were
as the face of men.
So now, he can you can see men, you can
see the pilot and co-pilot in a
helicopter. So John is describing this
with their helmets on. John is looking
at it, but he don't have nothing in his
day. He's just doing the best that he
can to describe what's going on in our
day, but he's using the things of his
day. That's all I got. So that's what
this bottomless pit and that's what this
Revelation 9 is really all about.
Eastern and Western European getting
ready to go to war.
Let me Let me throw something in.
All right.
>> The words the bottomless The bottomless
pit is a metaphor. Yes.
>> is
you got this big army over there in
Western Europe
because they going to be under the
European Union and they going to be in
control of 31 armies. Yes.
>> nobody know it.
And the world is not ready for this.
So when the Western Europe
attack Eastern Europe
It's just like
a big army come out of a hole in the
ground.
But now they're on top of the ground.
The pit is a metaphor is you have that
big army over there and don't nobody see
them because there nobody looking for
them because people don't know prophecy.
So they're on top of the ground, but if
you don't even know it and nobody knew
how big they are and all of a sudden
they go into action, it's just like
something coming up out of a pit
that's been covered and hid.
So
bottomless pit is a metaphor.
So this big army all of a sudden is
going to come up on on Eastern Europe
and the world going to see it.
And they didn't know that you had army
in this side in Western Europe. That's
all I have to say. Yes, sir. Thank you.
Oh, yeah.
News stations will be busy at that time.
Yes, so everybody going to know about
this. Going to be broadcast around the
world.
Yeah.
Yeah. All right.
Hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next.
Next one, Melanin Natural Journey asks,
"If you see someone for example eating
shrimps
but you don't say anything to them
because you are trying to avoid
conflict.
Can I pray for them instead?"
What you say?
Uh can you pray for them instead? I
think I think it would be better if you
could have a conversation with them
and and it can be done in a way
that
that fits the narrative because you
can't go around a restaurant
telling everybody that's eating unclean
things that it's
you know, it's an abomination to them.
That's That's not what we called to do.
So, let's go to uh Galatians 6 and we
just going to read verse 1 there.
Galatians 6 and 1.
Go ahead when you get it, Tangel.
Brethren, if a man be overtaken in a
fault,
ye which are spiritual, restore such a
one in the spirit of meekness,
considering thyself,
lest thou also be tempted.
And some people you can't restore in the
spirit of meekness cuz they going to
fight you back, especially if you is
unsolicited.
But if you all having a conversation
about it
and they profess themselves to be
Christians, then you could share with
them in the word of God. Let's go over
to Titus the 2nd chapter now.
Titus 2, we going to read verses 11 and
12 and then 15.
Get when you get it, go ahead, brother.
Okay.
I'm just in Titus 2.
Mhm.
11 and 12.
For the grace of God that bringeth
salvation
hath appeared to all men,
teaching us that denying ungodliness and
worldly lusts, that we should live
soberly, righteously, and godly in this
present world. Hey, this is This is what
we called to do.
And even if you don't know it and you
know it, then you share with them
because Leviticus 11,
you know, 9 through 11 tell you that if
it don't have fins and scales, it is
unclean. It even says it is an
abomination unto you. Right. But read
verse 15, brother.
These things speak, and exhort, and
rebuke with all authority.
Let no man despise thee.
And sometimes you have to rebuke with
all authority. But at the same time,
you know, you can't just go around
telling everybody that don't want to
hear
what the book say.
You know, but the book says open rebuke
is better than secret love
in in Proverbs. Right.
>> Because it is love.
So praying for them, it would be better
if you could have a conversation with
them.
Uh
I really want to go to one last place.
Let's Let's go Let's go over to 2
Timothy 2.
2 Timothy 2
read verses 24 to 26. That's it.
And the servant
Okay.
And the servant of the Lord must not
strive,
but be gentle unto all men, apt to
teach, in patience,
in meekness in meekness, instructing
those that oppose themselves.
If God peradventure will give them
repentance to the acknowledging of the
truth,
and that they may recover themselves out
of the snare of the devil,
who are taken captive
by him at his will. Yeah, because the
devil is taking captive the minds of
people and twisting some of the New
Testament writings of Paul saying that
you can eat anything. All you have to do
is pray over
But you you know, if you given the
opportunity to share, of course you
should share.
But I don't think you should just go
around
hitting everybody that you see. That's
That's all I got.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered their question.
Next one.
Next one. Be alert as is it okay to eat
food made for Christmas parties?
Nope.
Because they've taken that whole day and
made it all about the birth of Christ.
And um
it has nothing to do with Christ
Christmas. Because if you go go there
and you go eat the food that's made
you know, for the Christmas party. Then
come the music. Chestnuts roasting on an
open fire. Then come the gifts.
Then come all this good stuff to go
along with it and before you know, you
jamming right along.
Let's go into Jeremiah 10 and explain it
just a just a little bit on what this
day stands on.
And so once you have come into the
knowledge of the truth then you have to
separate yourself
from that day.
Jeremiah 10 and let's pick up verse 1 10
to 11. Go ahead.
Hear ye the word which the Lord speaketh
unto you, O house of Israel.
Thus saith the Lord, learn not the way
of the heathen.
And be not dismayed at the signs of
heaven.
For the heathen are dismayed at them.
Uh-huh.
>> customs of the people are vain.
For one cutteth a tree out of the
forest,
the work of the hands of the workman,
with the axe.
They deck it with silver and with gold.
They fasten it with nails and with
hammers, that it move not.
And then most of those parties always a
tree there
somewhere where they deck it with silver
and gold. And if not, then hey, they got
mistletoes or something. But you should
read up on what all Christmas mean. Go
ahead.
They are upright, as the palm tree, but
speak not.
They must needs be borne, because they
cannot go.
Be not afraid of them for they cannot do
evil.
Neither also is it is it in them to do
good. Verse eight, that's it.
But they are all together brutish and
foolish.
The stock is a doctrine of vanities. A
waste of time, don't have nothing to do
with even what are the reason they
celebrating it. So, no. You shouldn't be
going in participating and eating the
food and bring your own potluck lug dish
and all that stuff. Cuz it has nothing
to do with Christ by any means.
That's all I got. Anybody else?
Yeah, you know, uh
Paul spoke of something like this. Maybe
somebody can find it where he said,
whatever somebody put in front of you,
eat asking no question. But if they said
if this is to uh
uh some god, then don't eat it. Can
somebody find that right quick?
All right. Search more for that.
I think that's the perfect answer for
the question that was asked.
Some about for conscience's sake, right?
Yeah, where he said, don't eat it,
period. You know.
He said, if they whatever they put in
front of you, eat it asking no question.
But if they said if this is to some god,
uh uh uh
then don't.
Exactly.
What was that?
First Corinthians uh 10.
Well, let's look at it.
First Corinthians 10 and uh
is it 25
to 27?
No, 27 verse, 27.
1 Corinthians 10
>> 10 and what? 27.
Okay.
Uh
You want to start it?
Start at 27? Yeah, 27, 28.
If any of them
Go ahead.
If any of them that believe not bid you
to a feast
and you suppose to go
to whatsoever is set before you eat
asking no question for conscience sake.
But if any man say unto you, this is
offered in sacrifice unto idols, eat not
for his sake that show it
and for conscience sake
for the earth is the Lord's and the
fullness thereof.
So, that's the answer to the question.
If this food for Christmas, that's
that's
offered for to a pagan god, then you
don't eat of it.
Well, I had a uh
years ago, I had a neighbor
that invited me to a Christmas dinner.
And I was turning it down and told him
why. He said, "Well, I'll name it to a
call it the annual dinner." I said,
"Okay, then have it in August."
That is right.
And they cut that out. So, now, if it's
going to offer to a pagan god, that's
why you don't eat it.
Even if your mama getting mad at you.
That's all I have to say.
All right.
Let's move on to our next question with
a time check.
Yes, the time is 8:10. Next question.
Robert Dosch asks
is there a scripture that reads, you
place trust in no man, not even
yourself.
All right.
All right. Yeah, let's let's go over to
uh
Jeremiah.
Yeah, Jeremiah 17.
And and read verse 5. Jeremiah 17 and 5.
When you get there, go ahead, brother.
Thus saith the Lord, "Cursed be the man
that trusteth in man and maketh flesh
his arm, and whose heart departed from
the Lord." So, he's saying that don't
trust man more than you do God and and
uh your heart departs from the word of
God. Verse 7. Go ahead.
Blessed is the man that trusteth in the
Lord and whose hope the Lord is.
That's it, right there. Now, let's go
over one uh Psalm 118.
Psalm 118, we're going to read verses 8
and 9.
Go ahead when you get it, brother.
It is better to trust in the Lord than
to put confidence in man. Mhm. It's
better to trust in the Lord than to put
confidence in princes. That's right. So,
it's better to trust in the Lord.
And as far as you trust in yourself,
let's go over to uh Proverbs 3 and read
verses 5 to 7 and that's it.
Proverbs 3,
verses 5 to 7.
Go ahead, brother, when you get it.
Okay, Proverbs 3.
And you said 4 to 7? 5 to 7.
Trust in the Lord with all thine heart
and lean not unto thy own understanding.
In all thy ways acknowledge him.
And he shall direct thy path.
Be not wiser than own eye.
Fear the Lord and depart from evil.
That's right. So simply, you know,
trust in the Lord and you know, trust in
the Lord above all things. Right. And
lean not to your own even with your own
understanding cuz most times it's our
own understanding
that gets us in trouble.
Right. So he's simply saying trust the
Lord. That's it.
That's right. Like the book say too,
Dre, sometimes a man leaning to his own
understanding and the ways they're in
could be death, right?
>> That's right. The way that seemeth right
to man.
That's right. Yes, sir. So thank you for
that, brother, as we move on to our next
question.
Next question, Skywriter asks, "What
does it mean, look not upon me cuz I am
black because the sun has looked upon me
in Songs of Solomon 1?" What is this
talking about?
All right, look not upon me because I am
black in Songs of Solomon 1. Let's go
there, brother Tanzael.
To the Songs of Solomon.
You got Proverbs, Ecclesiastes.
Then you got the Songs of Solomon 1
and pick it up
at that verse 1 and go ahead and let the
guest caller take it from there.
The Song of Songs, which is Solomon.
Let him kiss me with the kisses of his
mouth.
For thy love is better than wine.
Because of the savor of thy good
ointments.
Ointments.
Thy name is as ointment poured forth.
Therefore, do the virgins love thee.
Draw me, we will run after thee.
The king hath brought me into his
chambers.
We will be glad and rejoice in thee.
We will remember thy love more than
wine.
The upright love thee.
I am black, but comely, O ye daughters
of Jerusalem,
as the tents of Kedar, as the curtains
of Solomon.
Look not upon me, because I am black,
because the sun hath looked upon me.
My mother's children were angry with me.
They made me the keepers of the
vineyards, but my own vineyard have I
kept not.
Or not kept.
>> all that reading, or did it stop with I
am black, but comely?
What is the last reading there? What
Verse five.
Is where it stopped there?
I stopped at six.
Okay, but the question was to five,
right?
Yeah, I think the question was
Oh, wait. Sorry about that. No, they
were just talking about what does it
mean about I am black because the sun
have looked upon me.
Which was also in that six, but five
picks up black, too.
But was was six a part of it, the
question?
Yeah.
Okay.
So, uh
uh uh
Re- read five and six again, then.
Okay.
I think it was the uh the middle of the
the first half of six.
I am black,
>> Okay.
but comely, O daughters of Jerusalem,
as the tents of Kedar, as the curtains
of Solomon.
Look not upon me,
because I am black, because the sun hath
looked upon me.
You know, really, this is Solomon wrote
this,
but this is talking about Jesus. He is
the one that say he is black but comely.
And the word because the sun because the
sun is looking the sun look upon me,
that just a metaphor. Anybody ever laid
out in the sun and got black? You might
have got sun cancer or skin cancer.
So, what he said, he said, "I'm black
but comely."
He is Do you know that he is actually
black?
Why? Because Jesus was an Israelite just
like Solomon was an Israelite.
And let's go and show you
who the Lord said the Israelites look
like. Let's go into Amos the 9th chapter
and verse 7.
That Hosea, Joel, and then Amos.
Amos 9 and 7.
Are ye not as the children of the
Ethiopians unto me, O children of
Israel? saith the Lord.
Have not I brought up Israel out of the
land of Egypt? And the Philistines from
Caphtor, and the Syrians from Kir.
So, now, he likened Israel to the
Ethiopia.
The Ethiopian come from the word Ethiop.
So, when when the
Greeks look upon looked upon the
Kushites,
which is Ham's oldest son, Cush,
they said, "These people
have burnt faces."
And and
and and the Greek word for that was
Ethiop.
So, he said, "Look, the Lord said we are
as the Ethiopians." The Ethiopians are
black folks.
And the sun looking upon somebody,
shining on somebody, do not make anybody
black. He was just telling you This is
the Lord telling you by the mouth of
Solomon what color he was and that is
black.
But the sun is merely a metaphor.
That's all I have to say.
All right.
We've then answered your question as we
move on to our next one.
Next one, be alert asks, are the books
of Mark and Luke, are they
disciples?
Were they first-hand witnesses to Jesus'
min- ministry?
All right, brother Julius.
Yes, they were disciples. Disci- The
word disciple means followers. That's
all it means.
The That's That's all it means and
whether they were first-hand witnesses,
yes and no.
Yes and no, because you got Mark and you
got Luke. They both got the writings
and they both hung out with Peter and
them and they hung out with the
disciples. So,
let's go to Acts 11th chapter.
Just like we are today, we weren't
witnesses to Jesus, but we follow him,
don't we?
That makes us disciples. Right.
Followers of Christ.
Acts 11, read verse one and then we
going to skip.
And the apostles and brethren that were
in Judea heard that the Gentiles had
also received the word of God.
So now,
news got back to everything that they
were ministering and it got back to
Jerusalem. Verse 22.
Then tidings
Verse 22? Yes, sir.
Then tidings of these things came unto
the ears of the church which was in
Jerusalem. Uh-huh. They sent forth
Barnabas and he should go as far as
Antioch.
And what happened at Antioch at verse
26?
And when he had found him, he brought
him unto Antioch. And it came to pass
that a whole year they assembled
themselves with the church and taught
much people. And the disciples were
called Christians first in Antioch. So,
that's what a Christian is, a follower
of Christ. So, Mark
and Luke
and all the scriptures in the Bible, all
the books that's named, Paul was a
Christian.
You know, and we profess to be
Christians.
So, so was Mark and so was Luke,
That's all I got, Cornelius. Followers
of the Christ.
All right. All right, here against
caller. Yes, caller.
But you also they said they was
witnesses, right?
Yes, sir.
>> Yep.
You know, like what they say,
eyewitnesses?
Firsthand. Were they firsthand
Well, let's go in the 2 Peter the first
chapter.
Yes, sir. I got that down, too.
2 Peter 1
1 Peter the first chapter uh 2 Peter the
first chapter and start reading at verse
16. Yes, sir.
For we have not followed cunningly
devised fables, but we made known unto
you the power and coming of our Lord
Jesus Christ,
but were eyewitnesses of his majesty.
So, that says that that and that
correct? Yes, sir.
They was right there with him?
Right. So, let's see.
All right.
We're going to move on to our next
question. Yes, moving on. Uh Beyonce
Antoine says, if we are not going to
heaven, what does Matthew chapter 5 mean
by the kingdom of heaven in verses 10
and 20? People use verses like these to
try to prove that we're be that we will
be in heaven.
All right. That
Matthew 5, you ain't going there.
Matthew 5 and pick it up at that verse
and then skip down, brother, to verse
20.
Hey, Matthew 5 and 10.
Blessed are they which are persecuted
for righteousness' sake.
For theirs is the kingdom of heaven.
Verse 20.
For I say unto you
that except your righteousness shall
exceed the righteousness of the scribe
and Pharisees,
ye shall in no case enter into the
kingdom of heaven.
Now, this kingdom of heaven is talking
about the Father's kingdom.
Not talking about Jesus.
For Jesus' kingdom is going to be on
this earth for 1,000 years. So, the
kingdom of heaven is the Father's
kingdom,
which right now
is in heaven, but we're going to show
what's going to happen with this
kingdom.
Let's go into Revelations.
The uh
uh uh
Ooh.
Revelation the
uh uh uh
21st chapter.
And we're going to read 1 through 3
first.
Revelation 21 verses 1 through 3.
And I saw a new heaven and a new earth.
For the first heaven and the first earth
were passed away, and there was no more
sea.
And I, John, saw the holy city, New
Jerusalem, coming down from God out of
heaven,
prepared as a bride adorned for her
husband.
And I heard a great voice out of heaven
saying, "Behold,
the tabernacle of God with men.
And he will dwell with them, and they
shall be his people, and God himself
shall be with them and be their God.
Keep reading.
And God shall wipe away all tears from
their eyes.
And there shall be no more There shall
be no more death, neither sorrow, nor
crying.
Neither shall there be any more pain.
For the former things are passed away.
Now, it tell you it show you that
the New Jerusalem is coming down from
God out of heaven.
And it said that God is going to dwell
with man. Is this what we just read?
Yep. Yep.
So now, he going to bring his kingdom
down to us.
I skip down to verse 10.
From 10 to 12.
And he carried me away in the spirit to
a great and high mountain.
And showed me that great city, the holy
Jerusalem, descending out of heaven from
God,
having the glory of God, and her light
was like unto a stone most precious,
even like a jasper stone clear as
crystal.
And it had a wall great and high,
and had 12 gates,
and at the gates 12 angels,
and names written thereon,
which are the names of the 12 tribes of
the children of Israel.
Go ahead.
On the east
three gates, on the north three gates on
I'm sorry.
On the 12 tribes, so they show you again
that the same
New Jerusalem, which is kingdom of the
Father, kingdom of the Father is coming
down. Right. And it's got 12 gates.
Isn't that right? Now look down at verse
and continue.
And the 12 gates were 12 pearls.
Every several gate was of one pearl, and
the street of the city was pure gold,
as it were transparent glass.
Let me interject something. People
talking about you going to walk on the
streets of gold, right? Right. And
you're going
at the pearly gates. Isn't that correct?
Yeah.
So each gate was a pearl, and the street
was as gold as transparent. Go ahead and
read.
And I saw no temple therein.
But the Lord God Almighty and the Lamb
are the temple of it.
And the city had no need of the sun,
neither of the moon to shine in it, for
the glory of God did lighten it. And the
Lamb is the light thereof.
And the nations of them which are saved
shall walk in the light of it. And the
kings of the earth do bring their glory
and honor into it.
Oh, so this is on earth, isn't it?
That's right.
So you ain't going there.
Mhm.
>> It is coming. The Father's kingdom, that
kingdom of the Father's kingdom, and it
is coming down to us. And if you find
yourself in that kingdom, then you are
immortal.
And even the kings of the earth, they're
still going to have
nations but the Lord set that up in the
beginning like he wanted. The only
difference is they're going to be
immortals.
And the Father's going to bring his
kingdom down here. That's why he said
he's going to dwell with man but at that
time we won't be called man. We will be
called God.
And it's all going to take place on this
earth.
That's all I have to say.
All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
Moving on. The alert wants you to
explain Nahum 2 verses 11 and 12.
All right. Nahum 2 verses 11 and 12.
Let's go to that 10 zeal. You got Jonah,
you got Micah and then you got Nahum.
Let me get there.
and verse 11 and 12.
Nahum and
uh
Man, ain't been in Nahum in a minute.
Yeah, you got Jonah there and Micah. And
Nahum.
Uh make Nahum uh
2 and What was that? 2 and
11 and 12.
>> 2 11 and 12. Start it Go ahead guest
caller, take it from there.
Where is the dwelling of the lions and
the feeding place of the young lions
where the lions, even the old lions walk
and the lions whelp and none made them
afraid.
The lion did tear in pieces enough for
his whelp
and strangled for his lioness and lion.
And filled his holes with prey
and his den with raven.
You said Nahum 2 11 and 12?
Yeah. Kind of kind of
Kind of we
>> It slipped me. Let me see if I can look
at it. Nahum 2:11 and 12.
One of these little books in the back
that I never look at.
I don't know how they get
I think they got by me.
Right after
Yeah. Right after Micah.
You got Micah and then you got Nahum.
And then Habakkuk.
Yeah.
Right after Habakkuk.
So we going to examine examine this 11
and 12.
Where is the dwelling Oh, where is the
dwelling place of the lion?
And the feeding
Uh uh
uh let me see in the Where is the
dwelling place?
Where is the dwelling place?
On the lion The dwelling of the lion and
the feeding place.
And the feeding place of the young lion.
Where is the
Where is the lion, even the old lion
walk? And the lion's
whelp, and none made them afraid.
The lion did tear in pieces
enough for his whelp
and strangled for his lioness
and filled his hole with the prey.
And his den with raven. Okay, we When
I'm looking at these these lions, that
let me know that they are not in the
zoo. The where the dwelling place of the
lions that they do all this stuff?
In the jungle.
That's the answer to the question.
All right.
We'll leave it there as we move on to
our next.
Moving on. Humility
Humility
uh, gives Exodus 24 verse 11 saying,
"They did see God and drink." However,
Exodus 33
verse 20 says, "Thou canst see my face
and live." What changed?
All right. Brother Jerome?
Um, let's go and take a look at the the
verses of Exodus 24
and 11.
Exodus 24:11?
Yeah, actually pick Can you pick it up
at the 10 and read it to the 11?
Okay.
Uh, and they saw the God of Israel, and
there was under his feet, as it were, a
pavement work of a sapphire stone.
And as it were, the body of heaven in
its clearness.
And upon the nobles of the children of
Israel, he laid not his hand. Also, they
saw God and did eat and drink.
Okay, well, right there it said they saw
God, but it didn't say they saw his
face.
Right. Okay, and then it said that uh,
in that 10th verse he said, "And under
his feet,
uh, as it were, a paved work of sapphire
stone, and as it were, the body of
heaven in its clearness." So, they saw
him, but it they didn't see his face.
Okay, now, let's read that other verse
that was given. What was it? Exodus 33?
Yeah,
and 20. Yeah.
33 and 20?
Yeah.
And he said, "Thou canst not see my
face, for there shall no man see me and
live."
So, uh,
he was talking to Moses there, and Moses
didn't see his face either. But when you
keep reading, he said he saw God.
So, read verse 21 through 23.
And the Lord said, "Behold, there is a
place by me, and thou shalt stand upon a
rock.
And it shall come to pass when my glory
pass by, that I will put thee in a cliff
of the rock, and will cover thee with my
hand while I pass by.
And I will take away my hand,
and thou shalt see my back parts, but my
face shall not be seen."
And that's all I got on it.
Yeah.
All right.
Thank you for that, brother. Our next
question, please. Next one. Bread Brad
says, "I have a young friend that's
learning the truth.
They wanted to know if working at a
barbecue restaurant is okay to work at.
They worry about touching and selling
pork."
Yes, caller.
The only thing I can say
is that
uh uh uh
go read the 23rd chapter of Leviticus.
And the Lord tell you uh not to eat it.
What are you doing right there?
But when it come to uh
touching an unclean animal,
then
let you go somewhere else.
In fact, uh uh uh
later on is the question going to come
up concerning that thing, same thing
about touching.
Lord tell you not to eat it.
I can't tell you anything else. 23rd
chapter of Leviticus, read that.
And then, uh you have to stand for
yourself on that.
All right.
We're going to move on to our next
question.
Yes, moving on. Uh even though
Thanksgiving has passed,
this question is from Charlotte. She
asked, is it okay to have Thanksgiving
dinner with family?
And the second question
Excuse me, it's Kohler. Let's go back to
I said 23rd chapter. It's 11th chapter
of Leviticus.
>> Leviticus 11.
Yeah, you should have corrected me.
Okay, Leviticus
chapter. Go read that.
Yeah. And Deuteronomy 14th chapter.
Yeah. Okay, you
All right, Deborah, take it from the
top.
Yeah, Charlotte asked, is it okay to
have Thanksgiving dinner with family?
And her second question is, what does as
often as you remember me, we're to have
communion mean?
All right, so
Julius,
Thanksgiving has come and gone, but next
Thanksgiving, what you say? If you want
to
you can have Thanksgiving dinner with
your family. Thanksgiving is a civil
day.
Uh
as a matter of fact, 13 nations, at
least 13 nations
have a
harvest festival or what they call a
Thanksgiving day. It's just a day
ordained by the government.
Uh
supposedly giving thanks to God for the
crops and everything that come in. So,
it's a civil day.
It's only pagan if you add stuff to it.
And the answer to your second question,
let's go to 1 Corinthians because
let's go to 1 Corinthians 11th chapter,
brother
Tenzel.
1 Corinthians
chapter 11.
>> And we going to pick this up at verse 23
to 26 because uh the question was
uh what does it as often as you remember
me
we'll have to do uh we're to have
communion.
That's not scripture.
This is talking about the Passover.
Let's go and read verse uh 1 Corinthians
11 and read 23 to 26, Tenzel.
For I have received of the Lord that
which also I deliver unto you,
that the Lord Jesus, the same night
in which he was betrayed, took bread.
Uh-huh. And when he had given thanks, he
brake it and said, "Take, eat of this is
my body,
which is broken for you.
This do in remembrance of me."
Now, it is said nothing about communion.
They are observing the Passover.
Has nothing to do with communion. They
are observing the Passover. Notice
the bread, notice the wine. Keep
reading, brother.
After the same manner also he took the
cup, when he had sup saying,
"This cup is the new testament in my
blood.
This do ye as often as ye drink it in
remembrance of me."
Now,
go ahead at 26.
For as often as ye eat this bread, ye
drink this cup, ye do show the Lord's
death till he come.
So now, he didn't say do it often, he
says as often as you do this. Right.
What this? Let's go to Leviticus the
23rd chapter.
And let's look at what the Lord got
written in his word on when to keep and
observe the Passover, not communion.
Right.
Leviticus the 23rd chapter and we going
to read verse 4 and 5. Leviticus 23
4 and 5. When you get it my brother go
ahead and read it. These are the feasts
of the Lord, even holy convocation,
which he shall proclaim in their season.
In their what? Season. In their season,
not when you get ready to do it, but
when at the appropriate time. What was
they observing? Go ahead and read.
In the 14th day of the first month at
evening is the Lord's Passover.
Now,
on the 14th day of the first month at
evening is the Lord's Passover. That's
what they was observing. That's what
Jesus break the bread and he he gave the
and and and they drank the wine on the
Passover. How often do it come around?
Once a year.
So, whenever it comes around, the
Passover, then you
then you keep the uh you you you do
remember the Lord's death.
That's what this is all about because in
every in every generation sins have to
be passed over.
So, every year on the 14th day of the
first month at evening, we at the Israel
of God all over keep the Lord's Passover
once a year.
That's all I got Cornell.
All right.
Thank you for that as we move on to our
next question.
Next question, Britt Brad asked, is it a
sin to touch a football because it's
made from pig skin?
No.
I know.
Anybody else got something to add to
that? No. John the Baptist John the
Baptist wore camel's clothes. He didn't
eat the
He didn't eat the camel.
Go to Mark 3 and 4.
Matthew 3 and 4. Who read it?
Matthew 3
and verse 4.
And the same John had his raiment of
camel's hair
and a leathern girdle about his loins
and his meat was locusts and wild honey.
You know, John the Baptist was called a
prophet of the highest
because he was supposed to he was uh
Elijah to come in his time. So, he came
in the spirit of Elijah. So, he wore
camel's hair. Camel's hair is not
unclean. And look what the Lord did with
Israel in the wilderness. Go to Ezekiel
the 16th chapter and read verse 10.
Ezekiel the 16th chapter
Uh-huh, and verse 10.
I clothed thee also with bro- broidered
work and shod thee with badger's skin
and I girded thee about with fine linen
and I covered thee with silk.
Well, see, badger's skin is unclean,
too, just like a camel's skin. There's
some things you can do that the Lord
tell you not to do,
not to consume, but you can do other
things with it. The last place this
going to read it cuz the seventh chapter
and read verse 23 and 24.
Speak unto the children of Israel, ye
shall eat no manner of fat of oxen
or of sheep or of goat.
And the fat of the beast that dieth of
itself
and the fat of that which is torn with
beasts may be used in any other use but
ye shall not no wise eat of it.
Okay. So, there's certain things of
unclean beast you can use them, like
your bristle
on a a brush.
Or like John the Baptist wore camel
skin. Or like the Lord
put made shoes for all Israel out of
badger skin. They was all unclean.
But you couldn't consume them. That is
the difference.
That's all I have to say.
Mhm. All right. We can drink and wear
them gators.
That's it.
Yes, sir.
All right, brother.
All right. We're going to move on to our
next question. What is the time check?
Yes, the time is 8:44.
Sci-A-Moral
Israel asks, "Does Psalm 18:4-15
speak of God the Father coming down from
heaven?"
All right, brother Julius. In that
Psalms
does it speak about the Father coming
down?
Yes, it does.
Yes.
>> Yes, yes, it does. Let's Let's Let's go
look at why he came down.
Let's look at first why he came down
and what he did
when he did come down. Let's go to
Matthew the 27th chapter.
Jesus is being crucified.
And
he's in the flesh.
Matthew 27, let's read 45 to 47, Tenzel.
Matthew 27:45
to 47.
Now, from the sixth hour there was
darkness over all the land unto the
ninth hour.
And about the ninth hour, Jesus cried
with a a voice, saying,
"Eli, Eli, lama sabachthani."
And that is to say, "My God, my God,
why hast thou forsaken me?"
Now,
he said, "My God, why my God, why hast
thou forsaken me?"
David wrote about this
because Jesus had to fulfill every bit
of prophecy that he came to fulfill.
Now, let's go to Psalms, the 18th
chapter. We ain't going to read the
whole thing. We just going to read
enough for you to see this here.
Remember what he said, "Eli, Eli, lama
sabachthani."
Psalm
18, pick it up at verse six. Go ahead.
In my distress, I called
>> at verse five. Look what he was going
through, verse five. Go ahead.
The sorrows of hell compassed me about.
The snares of death prevented me. And
verse four said that uh he was uh uh uh
the sorrows of death compassed me and
the floods of ungodly men made me
afraid.
Cuz he in that flesh being tortured and
crucified. Verse six, go ahead.
In my distress, I called upon the Lord
and cried to my God, and he heard my
voice out of his temple. Yes. And my cry
came before him, even unto his ears.
Now, this is not talking about David.
This is talking about Jesus on the
cross. Go ahead. What happened?
Then the earth shook and trembled.
The foundations also of the hills moved
and were shaken.
>> Because he was wroth. Go ahead. There
went up a smoke out of his nostrils and
fire out of his mouth devoured. Coals
were kindled by it. Go ahead. He bowed
the heavens also and came down. He came
down. That's when the Father came down
to comfort his son. Go ahead. And
darkness was under his feet.
Man, and how did he get there?
He rode upon a cherub and did fly.
Yea, he did fly upon the wings of the
wind. One more.
He made darkness his secret place. His
pavilion round about him were dark
waters and thick clouds of the skies.
That's all I got. Yes, so this was about
when the Father came down.
Yeah.
And brother Julius said darkness too
still kept the scripture that no one has
ever heard his voice nor seen his shape.
That's what the darkness was for. Man,
he came down in darkness. It was
darkness all over the land. Go ahead.
>> Yep.
It's another place where they say
Uh there's another place too. It's in
the Old Testament. I think in one of the
small books where he said that uh
because of the be dark at noonday.
Amos.
Yeah.
>> Amos? Amos? Yeah. Yeah.
>> it. Amos.
Yeah.
>> Amos 8:9 say it's noonday and that
should be darkness. Yeah, I think it's
Amos 8.
And uh verse 9 I think is right to it.
Let's see. Let's go to that town there.
Because that's another
>> Yeah. Amos 8 and there.
We going
uh
read to
uh 8:9
we going because we going to point out
something here and we going to read just
a little more.
All right.
>> Okay, read.
Start at 9. Start at 9. Started at 9?
Yep.
And it shall come to pass in that day,
saith the Lord God, that I will cause
the sun to go down at noon,
and I will darken the earth in the clear
day.
And I will turn your feasts into
mourning.
And what what what feast are you talking
about? Feast of unleavened bread.
>> Unleavened bread.
Go ahead.
>> And all all all your sons into
lamentation.
That will bring up sackcloth upon all
loins
and baldness upon every head. That will
make it as the morning
of an only son
and the end thereof as a bitter day. So
who did they crucify? The only son of
God. That's right.
So that's why I said that's why it
turned dark at noon day. That's why
when when Jesus made that cry it was
dark. Because
the father come down like I said in the
sun and he comforted him.
And darkness was his hiding place. So
yeah, that was Jesus. That's all I got
to say. All right.
So sister Deborah,
are we taking a walk into new territory?
Uh yes, we are. We are now into
tonight's Q&A for Wednesday, December
the 3rd, 2025.
Shanquella Akul Joby asks, was Jesus
actually God over us while he was alive
on Earth? And then the father was over
him when he took him back. If that's not
right, can you help me understand their
roles better? Okay,
let's open that up to the panel. So the
first question there was what now? Was
Jesus actually God over us while he was
alive on Earth? He
wasn't God at all. He
was man. That's why he called himself
the son of man.
Let's go
into Matthew the 19th chapter. I want to
point something out here.
>> As in Matthew's 19
and uh
Or I call it say "Let me good."
Yes, it is.
Young man called it cuz I don't cuz
nobody pays attention to this. That's
why I told nobody ever pay attention to
Jesus.
Uh it'd be 19 and 6.
19 and 6, you say? 16.
16.
Okay, read it.
And behold,
one came and said unto me unto him,
"Good master, what good thing shall I do
that I may have eternal life?"
And he said unto him,
"Why callest thou me good?
There is none good but one, that is God.
But if thou will enter into life, keep
the commandments."
Now, why did he check this guy for
calling him good? Because he's saying
only God is good. There ain't no good
man.
So, Jesus in the flesh.
Yep.
He made it clear.
He came God came forth in the flesh, but
once he
and God was with us, but the whole thing
is that's kind of like a metaphor
because he said he took up on him the
seed of Abraham. Ain't that correct?
Mhm. Yeah.
And
as he became
Let's see. Ain't that Hebrews?
Hebrews 2.
Huh?
And Uh let's see.
The time when he
>> Uh yeah.
Hebrews Yeah, Hebrews 2 where it say
But we see Jesus who was made a little
lower than the angels.
Right, but I want to see the part where
he took up on him
uh uh uh
flesh and blood and made in the in the
likeness of Abraham.
Oh.
I know in Philippians it says who's in
the Philippians 2. Yeah, Philippians 2.
Yeah.
>> Just say read
That it it's it's what it says uh
for for verily he took not on him the
nature of angels but he took on him the
seed of Abraham.
Okay, that's one.
Okay. Then read Can we look at uh
Philippians 2 and 7? Yep. 2 and 7.
That's what you want right there.
Okay.
What's it say?
Philippians 2 and 7.
But he made himself of no reputation
and took upon him the form of a servant
and was made in the likeness of men.
Yep. Mhm.
And being found what? And fashioned as a
man he humbled himself and became
obedient unto death
even the death of the cross.
Okay, that's one but there's still
something in Hebrews or something about
the seed of Abraham I want to see.
Either Hebrews or Acts, one of the two.
Let me see.
All right, we're in search mode for
that.
Yeah, let's see.
Still in search mode.
Mhm.
Uh well, let's go Hebrews 1
and uh
uh
down in verse
14.
Yeah.
Mhm. Hebrews 1
Mhm.
and 14.
Are not Are they not all ministering
spirits? That's 2:14.
I think it's 2. It's
>> Hebrews 2 and 16 you want. Yeah. I read
that.
>> 14.
2 and 14.
Yes, sir.
Yeah, pick it up at 2 and 14.
For as much then as the children are
partakers of flesh and blood, he also
humble humble he also himself likewise
took part of the same.
That through death he might destroy him
that had the power of death,
that is the devil.
And deliver them who through fear of
death were all their lifetime subject to
bondage.
For verily
he took not on him the nature of angels,
but he took on him the seed of Abraham.
So now when he did that,
he the flesh and blood man.
And that's why Jesus called himself the
son of man. He never called himself God
one time while he was in the flesh.
Mhm.
Yeah. That's why
this man called
>> He said, "None good but God." So he was
a
man. That's why he called himself the
son of man.
Mhm. And he went back
God
when he came up from the dead, when he
rose from the dead.
He called himself son of man. Now let's
go to the Romans the first chapter and
show you when he came to son of God
again and became a son of God. Romans
chapter 1
and start reading at verse 1.
Romans 1 and start reading at verse 1.
Paul,
a servant of Jesus Christ called to be
an apostle, separated unto the gospel of
God,
which he had promised before by his
prophets in the holy scriptures,
concerning his son Jesus Christ our
Lord,
which was made of the seed of David
according to the flesh,
and declared
and declared to be the son of God with
power,
according to the spirit of holiness
by the resurrection of the from the
dead.
So, that's when he became the son of God
for the first time. I'm telling you with
power
and also a
God.
Resurrection of the dead. But, while he
was in the flesh, he was man and he made
that clear and he called himself the son
of man.
That's all I got to say.
All right.
So, with that, yeah, the second part is
so, what roles do Jesus and God play?
But,
the the one they were already
uh play. Well, the God and the Father
and the Son, but the God God is God,
Jesus God, but he's also
the high priest
like he's always been.
Let's go into Hebrews the 7th chapter.
And we're going to start reading at
verse 1.
Hebrews 7 and 1.
For this Melchisedec, king of Salem,
priest of the most high God, who met
Abraham returning from the slaughter of
the kings, and blessed them.
To whom also Abraham gave a tenth part
of all,
First being by interpretation king of
righteousness, and after that also king
of Salem, which is king of peace.
Mhm.
Without father, without mother, without
descent. Having neither beginning of
days nor end of life.
But made like unto the son of God,
abideth for priest continually.
Do now.
So, Jesus was Melchisedec. That because
the high priest.
And
and and and the one that became the
father, he took the role on as as
as
I can't call him the father, but
you they took certain roles. So, Jesus
is the high priest
and the son of God
and the father is the father.
That's why
when you pray to Jesus pray to father,
you don't pray to Jesus, you pray to the
father in Jesus' name because you have
to always go through the high priest.
Yes, sir.
The one praying to father and the other
one praying
the son, but before he became the son
and the high priest again, it was just
the one that became father and Jesus.
The
Jesus the high priest, but both of them
was God. One of the place, St. John the
first chapter and start reading at the
first verse.
In the beginning was the word.
And the word was with God. And the word
was God.
Mhm.
The same
Keep going.
Yeah, yes. The next verse, the same was
what? In the beginning with God.
All things were made by him and with
out him was not anything made that was
made.
So, now,
Jesus
was in the beginning with God and he was
God because God
is a family
just like man is a family.
Everybody on this earth
is man, m a n, whether it's male or
female.
And Jesus and the Father
is God.
Period. But, there's just two in the God
family right now.
The one plan that the chief executive
and his plan to execute the
uh uh uh
the one that execute.
Mhm. The chief executive is the one that
give the commandment and the high priest
is the one
that carries it out. Plus again, too, he
is the liaison
and a
advocate for man.
That's all I got to say. Mhm. All right.
We hope that answered your question,
Sister Deborah. One final question of
the evening.
Okay, sure. Uh Marquetta
Gay asks
She Okay, where is she?
Well, Marquetta, where are you?
Right, where is she? Uh yeah.
I can't seem to find her. She was right
after Sue Jolby.
Okay. You got another one you can
quickly to or we'll come back to that
next week.
Um no, not one quickly. So, the time is
uh 9:02.
All right. Well, if it's 9:02,
we have officially come to the end of
our program. We like to thank everybody
from all around the world who tuned in.
If you sent us a question and we never
chance to get to it, please don't
resubmit it.
The Sister Deborah will take it, put it
in rotation, and we will deal with that
question next Wednesday. So, until we
all come together again, be safe out
there, be blessed, stay prayed up, and
may the Lord have mercy on us all as
Brother Tenzel closes us out.
Our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come, thy will be done in
Earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread, and
forgive us of our debts as we forgive
our debtors.
And lead us not into temptation, but
deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom and the power
and the glory forever.
In Jesus' name we pray.
Amen.